aib.ie 2009-06-28

# AIB Bank - Privacy Statement - Privacy Statement

## Your Right to Privacy

Allied Irish Banks, p.l.c. and its subsidiaries ("AIB" or "we") fully respect your right to privacy in relation to your interactions with this website.

## Collection and Use of Information.

AIB will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your consent. We will let you know what we intend doing with your information before collecting it, so that you can decide whether or not to furnish that information to us.

Any information which is provided by you will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality and in accordance with the terms of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003, as amended from time to time.

If at any time after giving us personal information you decide that you no longer wish us to hold or use this information, or in the case that the information becomes out of date, you are free to notify us, and we will remove or rectify the information within a reasonable time and in accordance with legislative requirements.

You acknowledge and agree that in certain circumstances we may be obliged to disclose personal information relating to you to third parties, for example, in order to conform to any requirements of law or to comply with any legal process, as well as to protect and defend the rights of property of AIB, our licensors and/or our other customers.

Telephone calls may be monitored or recorded to ensure that we carry out your instructions correctly and to help improve the quality of our service and in the interests of security.

## Swift Payments

International payments and certain domestic payments are made by Allied Irish Banks, p.l.c. (“AIB plc”) via the Belgium-based **Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication** (SWIFT). SWIFT processes payments on behalf of financial institutions worldwide and is currently the only organisation providing such a service. All transactions processed in Belgium are replicated in a backup system ('mirror site') in the US. Maintaining a geographically separated back-up infrastructure to ensure continued operation is in line with international standards and supervisory requirements. On foot of official subpoena(s), transaction data held in the US 'mirror site' may be disclosed to US, or other authorities for the purposes of combating terrorism and other serious crime. Therefore, any information you provide to AIB plc in order to effect a SWIFT payment could potentially be disclosed to US authorities, and by instructing AIB plc to execute a payment, you are implicitly giving your consent to such a disclosure.  

## Use of Technical Information

Cookies are files which are transferred to your computer's hard disk by a website. Cookies can store information about your preferences and other information which you need when you visit a website. AIB uses cookies to monitor our website traffic, to ensure better service levels and in order to provide you with certain features such as the customised delivery of certain information. To prevent the use of cookies you should activate the facility which is available in most web browsers that enables a user to deny or accept cookies.

Statistical and analytical information collected through the standard operation of our internet servers and logs provides us with general and not individually specific information. AIB will make no attempt to identify individual users, or to associate any technical information collected with any individual user.

## Disclaimer

AIB, its directors, employees, servants and agents, affiliates or other representatives and their respective parent and subsidiary companies, shall not be liable in respect of any claims, emergencies, demands, causes of action, damages, losses, expenses, including without limitation, reasonable legal fees and costs of proceedings arising out of or in connection with the use and/or dissemination of personal information relating to you in accordance with this privacy statement and your consents.

You should be aware that where you link to another website from the AIB website, that AIB has no control over that other website. AIB has no responsibility for the privacy practices of other websites.

## Amendments

AIB reserves the right in its sole discretion to amend this privacy statement at any time, and you should regularly check this privacy statement for any amendments.
